Contact

coreyrussell.bk@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/coreyrussell-84b9a0115 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Oncology Nursing
Oncology Clinical Research
Clinical Research

Certifications

Oncology Certified Nurse (OCN) Nurse-Executive Advance Master Certificate in Six Sigma, Healthcare

Registered Nursing License

Evidence-Based Practice: Making it a Reality in your Organization

Corey Russell

Director of Clinical Nursing, Hematology Services Houston, Texas

Summary

I possess a significant career background in oncology and progressive leadership experience. I excel throughout the complete spectrum of department operations management from staffing and budgeting, to quality assurance and continuous improvement.

I am extremely well-versed in direct patient care, patient advocacy, patient safety, nursing staff development, teaching, mentoring, and evidence-based practice (EBP). My knowledge of nursing practice trends and models is extensive, and I'm proficient in partnering with multi-disciplinary health care team members to increase safety and quality of care.

I've chaired numerous clinical nursing committees to assure continuous development and review of nursing standards and constantly monitor trends related to evidence-based nursing practice to influence practice changes and improvements.

Experience

MD Anderson Cancer Center
Director of Clinical Nursing, Hematology Services
August 2018 - Present (1 year 11 months)

Houston, Texas

Emory Healthcare

Specialty Director, Oncology and Solid Organ Transplant March 2017 - August 2018 (1 year 6 months)

Greater Atlanta Area

Provide direct oversight of 365 FTEs, 5 Nurse Managers and 4 Clinical Nurse Specialists.

Championed opening of a 250 bed medical tower. Develop and implement oncology and solid organ transplant program's strategic goals and objectives. Ensure department operates within budget and in accordance with performance standards. Accountable for the quality and service outcome for

Page 1 of 4

units within the department. Lead the implementation of Daily Management Systems throughout the division using LEAN principles and co-lead other PI/ QA projects using LEAN methodology. Serve as the executive sponsor for the Professional Development Council, member of Magnet Steering Committee, nursing leadership representative for other inter professional councils.

New York-Presbyterian Hospital

Patient Care Director, Medical Oncology/Bone Marrow Transplant 2014 - March 2017 (3 years)

Championed opening of a 19-bed Medical Oncology Unit requiring onboarding of 45 direct reports and establishing processes and procedures to optimize workflow efficiency and patient safety.

Demonstrate exemplary leadership talents in mentoring new graduate nurses in Nurse Residency Program.

Delegate workload, supervise 90 FTEs, conduct regular performance evaluations, and encourage ongoing professional development to maximize quality assurance and clinical outcomes.

Led unit to exceed NDNQI benchmarks three out of four quarters in three nursing-sensitive indicators.

Chair multiple groups such as Nursing Practice Council and Oncology Clinical Practice Committee.

Promote and orchestrate improvement projects related to evidence-based practices and quality assurance.

Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center 8 years

Nurse Leader, Nursing Practice 2012 - 2014 (2 years)

Spearheaded full-scope operations within Center for Evidence-Based Practice (EBP) and Research.

Reinforced more than 500 Department of Nursing policies and procedures to enhance patient safety, regulatory compliance, and alignment with other internal clinical standards and operational procedures.

Introduced Lippincott's Nursing Skills and Procedures Manual to ensure policies remain up-to-date.

Proactively informed staff of practice changes via emails and department website.

Functioned as a resource and EBP subject matter expert for nursing staff during EBP improvement efforts.

Played an integral role in development of quality metrics for nursing standards.

Contributed to planning and determining operating and capital equipment budgets to meet nursing practice needs.

Served as nursing practice lead for Magnet Steering and domain specific work groups.

Served as member of several councils and committees spanning Chemotherapy, Clinical Device and Product Evaluation, Patient Safety, Nursing Quality Assurance, Nursing Informatics, Ambulatory Nursing, and more.

Chaired Department of Nursing Practice Council and selected as co-chair of Chemotherapy Nursing Practice Committee.

Clinical Nurse Specialist, Gastrointestinal Chemotherapy 2011 - 2012 (1 year)

Directed, mentored, coached, and supervised 35 FTE nursing personnel in administering chemotherapy to 130-150 patients each day according to rigorous patient safety policies and procedures.

Functioned as a clinical expert for chemotherapy administration and as a resource for patients, families, caregivers, and nursing and medical staff.

Strategically combined research utilization and quality assurance strategies to evaluate clinical practice for achieving optimal patient outcomes.

Promoted and participated in interdisciplinary approach to care delivery.

Participated in performance appraisal and competency assessment processes of designated nursing staff.

Research Nurse III, Phase I Experimental Medicine 2009 - 2011 (2 years)

Delivered operational and clinical leadership for Phase I clinical trials by preparing regulatory documents, driving cohesive efforts with regulatory agencies, and closely monitoring clinical documentation and source documents to ensure integrity and compliance with requirements.

Proficiently performed clinical management of symptoms and side effects related to study drugs.

Outpatient Chemotherapy Infusion Nurse III 2007 - 2009 (2 years)

Exhibited outstanding patient relations skills in caring for patients undergoing chemotherapy.

Currently maintain this role per diem.

Travel Nurse, Bone Marrow Transplant Service 2006 - 2007 (1 year)

Adhered to nursing process to proficiently care for patients undergoing stem cell transplants.

National Institutes of Health Clinical Research Nurse - Bone Marrow Transplant 2002 - 2006 (4 years)

Provided direct care to patients undergoing experimental stem cell transplants as well as phase I, II, & III research trials.

Education

Drexel University

Master's Degree, Nursing (Focus in Clinical Trials Administration) · (2011)

Berea College

Bachelor's Degree, Nursing · (2002)